so about the honey ball suit sir hmm man
18 so I guess like three key bits just
maybe read out those main bits so
basically the put has gone somewhere and
encounters a layman sake and upon him
and the party asks the ascetic is one
who says what one who declares was in
the body responds friend one who says in
such a way that one stands having
disputed with nobody in the world but
it's God's Mara's and Brahmas but it's
ascetics and brahmins with this
generation of gods and humans and also
in such a way that dwelling detached
from sense desires that Brahman is free
from doubt has cut remorse without
craving for this about existence
perceptions are not underlying
like how'd you stop disputing with Mara
by taking out what belongs to Mara means
completely removing any appropriation
and ownership and you got your own eye
insights no so it's the mind completely
developed removed of any traces of greed
aversion delusion so then you it's
inconceivable to have a dispute
internally let alone externally she does
actually refer to just all dispute
it's my dad and answer to them
any conflict yeah any discrepancy yeah
you're free from any dispute is a
discrepancy the common sense dispute but
the way they use is it's quite clear
that it applies even to the level of
that internal sense basis did belong
tomorrow mm-hmm and you're disputing
with murder by claiming the ownership of
all over those things and it's there's a
discrepancy so the butter finish isn't
says friend I'm one who says this so the
butter then do you have a question about
that particular battle okay so then the
butter goes away and speaks to the
bhikkhus and tells them about his
encounter with the parley and in
response to that one of the bhikkhus
says but panting the Buddha is one who
says what such that he stands having
disputed with nobody in the world but
it's God's Mara's bronze ascetics and
Brahmins with this generation of gods of
humans and also how is it that the
Buddha dwelling detach from sense
desires is that Brahman who is free from
doubt has cooked remorse without craving
for this about existence and perceptions
are not underlying so the bhikkhu
response oh sorry the Buddha response
says picking for what reason are
proliferated perceptions and concepts in
play for a man if there isn't anything
to delight him - welcome - attached to
here just this the end of the underlying
tendency to passion
just this is the end and the underlying
tendency to repulsion
the underlying tendency to views the
underlying tendency to doubt conceit
underlying tension tendency to for being
and the underlying tendency to ignorance
just this is the end of taking up sticks
taking up swords disputes quarrels of
arguments criticisms founder thought
speech these evil unwholesome things
cease without remainder yes it's not a
removal of the conflict it's about a war
of the basis of conflict the
proliferation of diversification it's on
the level of perception so the result of
your perception mm-hmm in which case all
you need to do is just stop engaging
with the results of your perception and
thinking you're somehow undoing a buncha
soper punches on the level of thing
being perceived that's where you want to
perpetuate you and do the being given do
the craving for being and everything
else and by that I mean the meaning
significance emotional value in regards
to things that are being perceived
that's what the punch a is dependence
your dependence on ownership is what the
punches can see if I show you I don't
know a watch I random watch okay so
watch but you don't feel anything
towards so your perception the meaning
of that perception the significance of
it is all it's not my watch and I don't
need the watch but now I show you a
watch given to you by your granddad that
he sort of survived two world wars and
you know made you promise you're gonna
look after it and you're emotional that
has so much significance to you it's
still the watch it's still a watch same
same perception of the same thing with
same usefulness but it needs much much
more yeah it's much more proliferated
meaning which means he has much more
proliferated pressure on you much more
proliferated on you much more proliferated being over
on you much more proliferated being over
you and that's what the bunch is and so
taking that even further well let's see
if somebody destroys the what you don't
care about would you be upset with them
no well that's the thing if somebody
comes and destroys the watch that you
emotionally engage with you will take up
the road and try to beat them up they
need to find other things that I there's
it in order to undo that the puncher
okay thinking about the watch thinking
about things didn't mean a lot to you
yeah that that's what are you lieutenant
for Pancho and you increase the
significance you know you forget about
your granddad you stop thinking about
him you won't you won't be experiencing
daily sadnesses and so on but imagine
you remove around those things yeah so
that watch would be constant reminder of
all the emotions thing again you're
going through so it's gonna grow a
punchable grow and increase so I just
gave the example of a random object in
the world that can be meaningful and
meaningless but there are certain things
that are always meaningful your life
your body your being your senses your
eyes your nose and that's already
proliferated yeah and if you wonder
whether it is or not what would you be
concerned would you suffer would you
experience mental anguish if you go
blind if you become disabled would you
be emotionally disrupted on account of
it
yes you would oh so to that extent the
meaning of these things have
proliferated into your own being so to
speak you are a and you responsible for
the proliferation that's not in things
perception is in things so to speak
receiving the watch perceiving things
with your eyes that you found to such as
the Buddha said in the scene there is
just the scene and for another hand in
the scene there will be just the scene
all the meaning the pressure the
emotional connection the ownership the
preparation has been fully depleted
destroyed removed for an arahant
things are still meaningful oh well
things are still meaningful on the level
of its own perception and you would
still have a memory that this watch used
to be very mean
important to me because he was given to
me by grandad so the significance of
things that's being perceived does not
disappear it's not like for another hunt
he doesn't know what what you saw yeah
he's just that pressuring burden of the
emotional significance has been now
uprooted but yes this is still an
important and extremely useful watch a
neuron might use it it might even know
it that it's his grants that's what
granted watch there's a proliferation
the per punch a side of things it's not
in things that you perceive not even
their significance in the use and their
intention ality yeah we thought that all
remains that remains completely and what
and that's what we said if you remove
the per punch oh yeah what's left is
like a tree cut off attitude so you
remove the life of this growth but what
has been grown stays petrified like
branches of a tree and that's what
people don't realize so they immediately
like jump in a conclusion like oh I must
throw away my possessions oh look you
have that phone no you must be attached
to it attachment does not mean
possession so to speak things the
meaning of this is that it's mine but
the meaning of mine does not have to
have an emotional influence over me but
that's much harder to discern because
it's such much easier to just throw away
the phone seemingly and that's the more
self-mortification comes as a result of
that attitude I'll throw in my
possession I'll throw me my wealth I throw away my
I'll throw me my wealth I throw away my
clothes I will throw in my eyes I will
destroy this body and that's how we'll
reach enlightenment no that's utterly
utterly misguided on the equal footing
as going to work the sense object like
sensuality is hence the middle way
so yeah if somebody else randomly has
demanded what's your teaching that's
exactly what we described that is the
teaching
could you say that in the particular the
removal top answer is basically the
removal of a whole sort of domain of
meaning that's the panel well let's let's put it
that's the panel well let's let's put it
in simpler terms the moolah per puncher
is on the basis of things that have an
emotional weight over you removal of
uttering all these things and that's
again it keeps matching in other talks
with you know the common views or look
everything is impermanent no that's
unimportant irrelevant whether
everything is things that are dear to
you are the ones you need to contemplate
and for being impermanent things that
will make you feel suffering if you lose
that and see that's what people don't
think about it even without losing
things just thinking about a possibility
of losing things that are dear to you
he's already suffering and that's what
popinjay is is that dearness so that
increases the more you are here to it
the less you question it the more you
refuse to look at it it grows because
the necessary basis for per punch a
growing is ignoring the function
ignoring the weight of this emotional
significance that has over me turning
away from it because it's unpleasant
ignoring your responsibility for it why
because responsibility is unpleasant so
if you want to undo per punch you need
to find things that are dearest to you
and start cultivating perception of
impermanence while those things are felt
as their to me yeah but before that you
need to practice sense restraint because
otherwise you you might go mad or
overwhelmed with anxiety and fear fall
on the ground beat your breast and pull
your hair as a suit is described and so
if you're if you're going to be
contemplating the nature of the body say
I think it's quite easy to forget you're
how and that's me that's always some
abstract notion of a you know objective
but I always criticize this like
meditation techniques
body sensations and watch inquisitive
person it's an unnecessary basis for
practice which is recognize the personal
involvement is completely taken away
repressed remove not acknowledged why
because it's unpleasant no don't don't
look at your knees and your shoulders
and sensations look at the value that
the body has for you would I suffer if I
die next five minutes if I find out on
my die next five minutes will I
experience anguish in fear no matter
sensation will reveal that to you
that's all secondary to your first and
foremost framework of your relationship
with that body so if you want to do a
meditation technique find the ways that
your own body is dear to you and then
question that by contemplating
impermanence in regard to it no 29 oh
look it's only permanent only permanent
that's my idea of this is dear to me is
a mistaken idea yes from another man's
point of view it's a mistaken idea
because here I'm done it
you haven't undone it so it's it's a
factual idea the mistake is real as a
mistake and unless you start
acknowledging it first all you do is
denying it and that's why you'll never
is over
okay so after the Buddha says that he he
goes off to his dwelling it's one of
those suitors where the bhikkhus like
what do you mean by no ended in asking
and they didn't ask him and they say who
should we should we ask and they yeah
Muraki channa he's good at doing this
thing he's always he's always explaining
in detail what the Buddha said in brief
that's going on skim and then he
reprimands them say one you cross the
border when you have the chance but I
will I understand he says I understand
the meaning in detail in this way hmm so
friends because of the iron sights high
consciousness arises the meeting of the
three is pressure right let's rephrase
that translation because of the eye and
sights consciousness is there
consciousness is manifested yeah because
they're the over rising means somehow
you can be aware of the process that
precedes your consciousness of the
process and that's a contradiction in
terms opacity so you are already conscious of
opacity so you are already conscious of
the sights means your eye is there sides
are the consciousness of those things is
there with those things not with you
yeah that's the point
oh I meets the sights and the spark
happens and that's consciousness yeah as
if you can even think that accurately
because you're it how's it possible how
can you be aware of the eye preconscious
I when only way of being aware of
something is being conscious of it
so when the description is given it's
not to explain the process now is to
just indicate the aspects of the
necessary basis for your thoughts and
perceptions and everything else on
account of the site it's the same
principles patty cheese on fire I'm sure
when is this is this yeah his eyes and
Sciences eye consciousness yes so eyes
sites eye consciousness simultaneously
there when there's like eyes insights is
just two ends of the same domain and so
to speak so eyes and consciousness
and when you is that there is the
emotional pressure in regard to the
scene you could say that eyes and sights
is sort of on the level of Rupa it is
yeah and then so and then I
consciousness there's a conscience when
there's that no in the meeting of the
three does this and that's the starting
point the pressure the pressure that's
women if you know the fact that you're
pressured by the emotionally significant
sites you then jump into the explaining
the sides so that you can dismiss the
pressure yeah
oh look I am pressure but what I've seen
I just thought sensuality or two or
three if you merely pause by it but see
it's just the I the sides and then
consciousness comes but that's this
pressure is not really real because
these things are no you get to discern I
sites and consciousness through the
starting point for you which is the
pressure that's your first point of
contact oh wait isn't it cold contact
exactly because it is that's the origin
contacted one feels contacted one gets
to perceive what gets intent all the
contact is not on the level of the
aggregates of feeling perception
intention you realize that everything is
sort of taken upside down and you being
pressured by the world by the senses by
everything else is the first point and
that's why keep saying you have to
acknowledge that basis because otherwise
you're just acting out of the idea of
what another hand is for you and trying
to like externally apply to your
situation by dismissing the problem in
front of you yeah first you need to see
the problem then see that removal of the
problem is without on ship is not like
the idea I develop oh that's what
factually other hand is and now I just
have to keep dismissing the problem
sufficiently enough until I become
another hand so yes from another point
of view contact is a mistake being
pressured by things is a mistake but you
are not in our hunt which means you your
mistake is your first contact and
whenever you whenever you dis pressure
and feeling that content doesn't
disappear know the context of it yeah
pressure
and and the only way that you can know
eyesight's and I consciousness exactly
so the meeting so them so yeah so in
fancy system to meet society's like the
energy as if you've been pressured the
necessary base where the pressure is
these three things being there yeah
together so to speak and with the
support of that pressure or contacts
picnic so the only way to understand I
sites and conscious correctly is through
the context of that meeting that is
understood through the context of that
pressure yeah so literally like you know
I don't know that I don't know like like
three of you for example I'm meeting
secretly behind my back I don't know
about it so I come there and I see you I
see him I see him
but I don't get the context that you're
there with a purpose that's you know if
I were to find that out yeah suddenly I
will see you I was to see him saying and
him but in that context ah they're here
together now so that's the first point
you need to recognize what the meeting
is and you recognize what the meeting is
by what what pressures you so through
the pressure you get to see the basis
okay so I am pressured by sites which is
in the level of eyes which means
consciousness is already there so let's
I mean those three aspects side some
besides eyes sites and consciousness can
only be understood correctly through the
context of the pressure that they
exhibit on you and that's a study let's
all get to undo the pressure sad irony
other hand does not become another hand
and he does not undo the pressure cuz he
destroys the eye objects or he pulls his
eyes out or he cans as his consciousness
no he just fully understands the basis
for the pressure and that's how he
doesn't experience the pressure anymore
the basis the remains for as long as the
body remains that's a foreigner and
there's this conscious body left and
they will matter everything else
externally
but if the pressure is seen as a product
of eyes eyes sights producing each other
consciousness we're talking exactly then
the pressure will be another natural
result of it and then you wouldn't be
able to uproot it you cannot remove the
pressure yeah but it's not the pressure
you being pressured by this basis by
this particular meeting so unless you
start seeing the context of that meeting
its you see there is no meeting if it's just
you see there is no meeting if it's just
you there is no meeting if you just him
by you coming together determine each
other's presence as the meeting yeah if
I'm unaware of the possibility of the
meeting I won't see that entire domain
of your connection and I'll just think
you're just a randomly individual it's
like it seems this is slightly different
from the first meeting because well I'm
going to simplify the thing we said
there's the I the sites and I
consciousness they can don't they they
can only good this will be a basis it's
not that they come first then they oh
yes oh absolutely that is this meeting
within that oh I can for somebody who is
I mean it's not an easy thing to
understand so I have to simplify the
external component speak but
fundamentally the only way you can know
the I or sites or consciousness is on
the basis of the meeting so and there
was like wiki coming at me and you
because of the me because yeah and if
you keep thinking of that than any
notion of I independent of the media
objects independent of the meeting
consciousness in depend of the meeting
will be seen as the wrong view yeah
because it cannot be independent of the
meeting the only way you can even think
it abstractly you know kind of it being
met already yes this meeting this
exactly so that's I mean even your
abstraction will be accurate if you
remove the wrong views you don't need to
stop thinking or something
no just will stop misconceiving things
even in your abstraction because they're
always rooted in the current contact
yeah in the current pressure in the
current basis of the experience as a
whole so that's I mean you can be
thinking about the eyes they operate the
consciousness and try to apply to
yourself but it it simply does not start
with the right basis and because of that
people not be accurate first you want to
find the pressure where where is the
emotional weight for you don't think
things you don't care about find things
you care about through those things you
can only discern I and objects and
consciousness and that's when the
suitors with the Buddhist monks do you
regard I to be yours no sir do you
regard objects to be no sir it's already
taken for granted that they only can see
these things through the my paces their
right view has been developed they don't
have the external assumption of the ID
the objects but when people don't know
the right over the right base is the
right order then they think oh yeah I
don't think I it's mine I don't think
objects as in objects I don't care about
are obviously not mine yes
I don't feel any pressure on account of
it so that's basically jumping the gun
so to speak yeah that's true in the end
for another hunt but you want to find
things that are dear to you the objects
that you do depend upon in them
emotionally and then start contemplating
the suitors the way when I said so
within that which is dear to you oh I do
see this is dear to me so how can I say
the eye is not mine the objects and of
mine when if they were to go I'd be
upset and anything like it's not it's
all other things set in stone that it's
always saying things that are dear to
poor people
some people can delight in something
that other people complete have no
problem letting go on and that's what we
could never prescribe everybody
everybody should be a forest water or
everybody must never go to the forest or
everybody because it depends depends
where your pressure is
yeah and the pump should be the previous
proliferation is the kind of what's
already been built up yeah it's all
about undoing that - trying to reroute
it's about uprooting the necessary basis
then everything else is left so that's
what I mean like even the Preferences to
some extent preferences based upon
centrality for example you approve the
sensuality the like the dried up
petrified directions of your preferences
are still there that's why other hands
could remember things on fun wholesome
nature in the past oh yes I used to act
out of fear and I was hiding in my
palace because I was fearing for my life
and who knows what else he was doing on
account of their fear he remembers that
but he feels none of it because he has
removed the basis of that that fear that
dependence on how he felt trying to
protect shelter himself from the
unpleasant feelings but doesn't mean
that he literally became like a
whiteboard there's no memory no
recollection of trace of anything
no no why used to really delight in this
now obviously funny disgusting but he
remembers that the extent of delight
that the descent of the perception that
grew as a result of him engaging him and
more with the meaning of it
they was pressuring him so removal of a
puncher does not remove the perception
the more of a bunch of does not remove
your thoughts so actually yeah that's
for the snake so with the suppose of the
contact of suppose the precious this
feeling what one feels one perceives hmm
what the see what one is seems like one
thinks about what one thinks about one
proliferate one proliferate okay because
of that but it's all within the pressure
yeah the basis of the pressure remains
holding all of these further factors in
the middle describes it's not that that
they cease once the next factor comes
they're all within the pressure you
remove the pressure there is no more
growth of the pressure through your
thinking and perceiving and revolving
around it yeah yeah if there's no
pressure there's no feeling if there's
no feeling there's no perceiving
thinking about no thinking about no
proliferation what won't proliferate
it's because of that proliferating
perceptions of concepts are in play for
a man in terms of sites that he could be
conscious on with the alley in the past
and future in the present and the same
fears and sounds so I think you could
you could summed it up by saying it's
not about thinking about what you
perceive that it's a problem it's about
thinking about what you perceived on
account of being pressured by it that's
the problem
so thinking out of the pressure is the
problem yeah not about what you think
and what movements your mind makes is
the fact that you're giving in to the
pressure and you want to get rid of the
pressure through thoughts and figuring
it out well thinking while that pressure
is there can you say the light but that
pressure is only there because you
weren't done yeah you have the thoughts
as a result of the pressure but that's
one thing and but you know as the Buddha
said you don't delight in the thought of
sensuality you don't entertain it you
don't engage with it sensuality is
already pressure yeah if you keep the
lighting in it yeah you're then
proliferating the pressure yeah you're
making it worse so to speak not if you
don't have the thought at all you can
you can't choose that thought is there
as a result of the pressure show but you
realize that's not up to me up to me is
whether I keep feeling the pressure
because if you stop feeling the pressure
the pressure will dissolve yes but you
can't just choose to cancel the pressure
by choosing to cancel the thought
because that's another thought rooted in
the same pressure so in people's are too
much thinking results in pain know too
much trying to escape the pressure
resulting more pressure because your is
wanting to escape pressure is rooted by
in the pressure
you wouldn't do so if you're not
pressured yeah so it's actually you will
acknowledge the pressure and then learn
how not to be pressured what pressure is
there that's why sense restrain is to
comfort that already enables you to
endure the discomfort to some extent
so much thinking is not the problem
learning how to too much acting out of
pressure is the problem yeah learning
how to not be pressured by the pressure
is the way I'll be patient if yeah if
you if you do that there is no pressure
yeah you won't be pressured that's
there's no pressure if I'm not pressured
by the price but if you if you start
saying no pressure anymore if you start
saying there's no pressure
yeah stop thinking stop the pressure
stop the pressure you do that out of the
pressure so you act out the pressure
means you feed the pressure yeah but it
has to be knowing the eel free so first
you have to acknowledge the pressure
yeah you have to acknowledge the
thinking and realize it that's not the
problem yeah scent your perceptions are not a
yeah scent your perceptions are not a
problem acting out of those is the
problem but you act out of those to some
cannon dude those perceptions for where
they are
so you give in to the pressure and by
giving it to the pressure you're
pressured by definition of it so you
have to acknowledge it and allow it to
be allow it to endure and that's how you
then learn how not to be bothered by its
endurance by its presence and that's how
it will wither away you you stop
engaging with it you stop feeding it
so he goes through the all the senses
the same that same sort of formula and
then there's just a swipe it
friends when there is an eye when there
are signs when there is eye
consciousness that the manifestation of
pressure will be discerned that is
possible when there is the manifestation
of pressure that the manifestation of
feeling will be discerned that is
possible when there is the manifestation
of feeling that the manifestation is
possible and you can also say the same
to craving okay there is no
manifestation of feeling there is
nothing to create for or against yeah so
you remove the pressure you remove
pressure being felt you remove the
pressure you remove that pressure being
felt being created against or for it so
you remove the pressure you remove the
suffering because by removing the the
craving in regard to pressure there is
no suffering anymore cuz that's what
suffering is it's not in the eye the
objects not in the consciousness it's in
you revolving around the pressure that
you're under I think that's why this
suit is sort of unusual like because
because it brings in the notion of
perception because there is the other
potential part of it did after craving
goes into taking up the roads and
fighting and killing each other and
leaves all the other factors out yeah
yeah so perception that the
manifestation of thinking will be
discerned that is possible when there's
the manifestation of thinking without
the manifestation proliferating
perceptions and concepts being play with
being in play you'll be discerned that
is possible
so that that's that the point there is
again it's not that the thing new things
perceptions grow the proliferation is
the meaning of those perceptions so say
I again back into the original example I
show you a watch means nothing to you
and you don't have any need for it but
then you get a need for a watch see the
perception of the same watch nothing he
didn't change the color or increase its
size yeah the perception is identical
but it means more it has more weight now
because there is a certain need that can
be met by that now imagine you they
really really become dependent on
knowing the time in every given moment
so you really dependent on having a
watch and now that watch is even more
meaningful to you then you find out
maybe that's also a very expensive watch
then you also find out they was owned by
the King of England or something like
that so it's extra valuable to all other
people and it's yours yet it's the same
perception of the same watch nothing has
changed yet everything has changed and
that's also when people if said like
difficulties understanding another hunt
thinking like you know he stops
perceiving and he just flies in the air
No so externally nothing has changed
internally everything has changed
because he's realized that's what
everything is whether it's pressure or
non pressure determines everything by
the petitioner or another whether you
with the grain of the pressure or
against the grain of the pressure as in
not pressured
yeah then he goes on to describe the our
hands so friends when there isn't
annoying and there aren't sites when
there isn't high consciousness that the
manifestation of pressure and you might
wonder so so why didn't the Buddha then
just stay and stick with the pressure
because it's your starting point for
practice it's the first point of contact
why did he tell you all the pressure is
dependent upon okay what do you think
that is why did you put a point in the
necessary basis for the pressure that is
your first point pressure is your first
point why do you keep reading I did the
necessary basis for it because you can
only undermine that necessary basis for
everything take the pressure
you can only undermine the pressure by
seeing that that is also passed
determined exactly by seeing that it
doesn't depend on you your choice your
attention by seeing that's subjected to
something that's not in your control
thus you being pressured is equally
subjected to that basis that's not in
your control
so everything everything that you that's
what if you think see that's where the
only intelligible relationship with I
objects in consciousness is to be seen
as a necessary basis for that which is
experienced so you don't experience I
objects and consciousness separately you
only get to discern it only the first
point which is the pressure there is no
lower point than the pressure yeah so
that's the some car government
mindfulness feeling the content
everything you cannot go below the
contact because that means you won't be
contacted yeah but that is what context
you so you're always within the
framework within the literally the
container of the context
or the pressure and I prefer pressure
because contact is impersonal oh that's
conduct see that's already pressure
isn't it yeah but you want to find that
it's not like exactly like emotionally
disinterest context because just gonna
happen to engage with it no it's the
emotional contouring the emotional
pressure so the Buddha described the
necessary basis for pressure because
that's the only way you can really
understand and get the right perspective
on that pressure and the stop being
pressure by it not because you need to
walk out of the pressure into the
necessary basis for it and somehow free
yourself from the pressure that's
impossible so the sin Cara's for the
necessary pressure that your experiences
for the first point the bottom is the
pressure the cicadas are basically the
right context how you should regard the
same pressure understanding the pressure
is only up understanding what it what is
determined by because at the moment you
see pressure pressures mind just acting
out of pressure it's also mine it's also
for the purpose of what I want to do and
so on but by seeing pressure is actually
not being in your control not being
mutiny already you're learning it's
correct nature and by doing so ordered
you were less affected by that pressure
is it conceivable to act out of pressure
if you're not pressured even if you act
towards those things you're acting would
that egg be rooted in the pressure if
you don't feel the pressure impossible
that's all in case you liked and that's
why I've been feeling exactly no
pressured feeling yeah that's the point
and that's hard and kids to choose and
prefer I don't like this so and eldest
person to go away
he's disagreeable yes he's a fool I
don't to spend my time with him oh you
know he must not discriminate no he can
discriminate none of his discrimination will be
none of his discrimination will be
rooted in being pressured by the
discrimination yeah sorry in one sense
you can say anything actually make the
effort and read the origin stories for
as in not you but the audience whoever
is interesting is about the rules you
see how discriminative the board
and even the language he used you would
think I remember first time I read it
because you know you get this as a
layman digital artifact basically just
this sort of energy of everything and
nothing and then you start eating this
like when the Buddha starts like
blasting the monks who you know
misbehaved better you should better use
the snake's mouth and whatnot how can
another hun speak like that because you
can't read them anything in between like
you can't because it's a factual right
thing to say and it varies routine
depression but he's not emotionally
disturbed on account of monks doing what
he says what monks not doing what he
says but he still oh this is
disagreeable this is stupid this is
foolish behavior
this is agreeable this is a good
behavior no by the way I'm not affected
by it because he's not pressure by and
that's also those cases about ants in
the sutras were people complained about
it because the way they were speaking
was rude and seemingly conceited and
arrogant and they were upsetting
everybody left and right they complained
to the Buddha and so no it's just
literally the habits of the speech have
left none of that is rooted in pressure
of vanity pressure of craving I should
concede used to work in the face yard
the other one was they always been born
in the higher Brahmin family and he's
just used to talking down he's literally
the habit of the speech so that's a few
judge things simply based on that yeah
nothing like there's nothing else that
you can deserve it in it yeah you're
missing out completely and you're not
seeing what the problem is and that's
when you will be blaming the eye and
decides for your pressure for your per
punch ah so then you think all I need to
do is a stop seeing and that's how we'll
approve the per punch of my sights yeah
the significance of my sight I'll get
rid of that oh there's gonna do this
pressure I'm painting
by getting rid of the basis of this
pressure I will get rid of the pressure
but the only way to know the base of the
pressure is through the pressure so in
practice all you're doing is acting on a
pressure which is what perpetuates the
pressure yeah the basis doesn't protect
you the pressure yeah
ignorance of the base is perspective the
pressure how can you know the basis if
you destroy the basis I can understand
the eye if you lose your eyes and sights
so better practice until it's too late
otherwise if pressure were truly rooted
in those things as a pressure that
crashes you death would be an are
hunting for everyone the structure of
the senses would be in the barn but
that's not the case
so the term for proliferation you could
use pressure as well well no pressure
proliferation is result of acting under
pressure I can see your pressure by
finding something you will meet your
need in other words your needs or as I
gave an example of needing the watch to
see the time it's already rooted in how
you feel about it and you're already to
some degree acting towards comfort
towards pleasant feeling so you need or
this item can meet that purpose so that
item becomes more significant mm-hmm and
the next time you perceive that item you
already perceive it within significance
you don't need to remind you the wait
what is this for
no next time you see the watch
especially if the purpose emotional
purpose emotional need is still there
any what you see will be seen with more
significance because that's what you
need it for you've been increasing the
value of this one yes we did the same
perception of the same thing mm-hmm
and the point when attending to the
contact it's like people like you said
people take what's impersonal and they
attend is impersonal phenomena and
they're like oh look at me I'm I'm
becoming free for sure you need to be
looking where the conceit is the
appropriation you need to find the
personal ones and then you realize that
any any correct form of practicing
impersonal perceptions can only be done
so within the framework of personal so
it's not about replacing personal with
impersonal it's about seeing impersonal through the
it's about seeing impersonal through the
personal that's the definition of some
Sankara Nietzsche sabes and Cara dukkha
sabe de ma anata but for most people
it's sabi Domenici sabudana dukkha
sabudana anata everything is impermanent
everything is played everything is
unpleasant everything is not self no
necessary basis is impermanent necessary
bases unpleasant your ownership is not
your own
so if you know the basis of ownership as
the starting point you'll be looking
these random things and just trying to
psychologize the nature
andrey explained it to you so it's that
way around you need to reverse the
picture by taking up what's first for
you and what's first for you is me my
sense of ownership
what pressures me emotional need
emotional dependence and then within
that emotionally so take a person that's
dear to you without ignoring the fact
that they did to you without stopping to
like ceasing to feel the dearness so to
speak think about bearing permits and
see how you're gonna feel about it it's
possible to attend to that proliferation
but not be beset by it
like if you have what you mean by
attending to it like you know
proliferation is occurring that the you
can proliferation is not occurring it's
already occurred it's already the basis
upon which you can either choose to act
wholly strain for but it's not like on
proliferation is a process yeah before I
guess like I would go these places that
speak about from the fashion people
assume proliferation to be on the level
of your mental activity so stop that
stop proliferate you know it's on the
level of meaning and pressure of things
that they exhibit over you so for
example things that you have not
emotional engagement they're not
proliferated for you but as I said you
start cultivating entertaining welcoming
acting out of a certain emotional
engagement with the simple same thing
same same perception of the same thing
that emotional dependence will grow so
the think the things that things did
that you they have already undergone a
fair result deliberation regards that
yeah because nothing would make it
announced to do with the meaning of that
thing it's not to do with anything I'm
doing right now is it so whatever you're
doing right now will be rooted in there
yeah so you saying you trying to stop
your thinking because you think that
that's how you stop a pancha
basically it's like saying oh so I'll
stop thinking about the pressure because
that's how I won't be pressured and the
only reason I want to do this is because
I'm you want to stop thinking about the
you want to stop thinking about the
pressure because you're already
pressured by the unpleasantness of it so
how do you stop thinking by thinking
about it it's a contradiction in terms
can you not think don't have any
thoughts in your mind now that's a
thought in your mind I must not have any
thoughts in my mind so it's utterly
futile like completely if you stop and
think about it no pun intended
this is impossible so you blaming the
result of pressure for the pressure
means ignoring where the pressure is oh
I'm not pressured it's only when I think
about the pressure are pressured so I'm
stop thinking about a pressure they were
feeling for pressure in other words I'll
ignore the pressure to be free from
pressure and that's the definition of a
reject out of discomfort you refuse to
address things not a discomfort you
ignore them out of discomfort you turn a
blind eye
it's like like throughout my day or even
weaker you know extra might throughout
my experiences it would be like okay
there will be certain kinds of thoughts
you know either about food or hunger or
you know a certain experience I would
like to re-experience mmm but I don't
like the time with that like if I were
to think about that right now
oh but I don't feel any pressure in
regard to that but then when there's a
certain discomfort that happens to me
yeah and then there's the pressure and
that's exactly the difference that
people will remain unaware oh for as
long as they think that the pressure is
in the perception the per punch is in
the perception it's not it's in regard
to but it's not perceived it's the
meaning of what you perceive so see you
have a random thought about of food
because you're actually hungry but there
is no pressure to eat you just had the
thought about a food there's no problem
with that then on another occasion you
ever thought about a food because you're
just full of sensuality and sensual
cream you're not even hungry yet you're
not pressured so in other words hunger
will not pressure you towards food as
much as you're craving would pressures
with food hunger and food is just out
there and you will never differentiate
that eating for the sake of hunger
anything for the sake of sensuality for
as long as you blame the thoughts of
food for sensuality for proliferation so
as I mean first you need to accept the
fact that the mind is thinking about
this and then you can see whether you're
thinking about it out of compulsive
pressure or are the factual necessity or
lack of spontaneous arising of those
thoughts but if every thought means
pressure every thought means
proliferation every thought must be
stopped you never see that the whole domain of
you never see that the whole domain of
middle-way you'll be blaming thoughts
and trying to cancel them or ignoring
them distracting yourself from one
distraction so that I mean are there
thoughts of food I must stop it now I
must see whether this is rooted as we
say in wholesome or rooted in
unwholesome listen whatever you know
to be unwholesome abandon it as in
whatever you know that it's rooted in
unwholesome that is rooted in pressure
don't cultivate it don't entertain it
don't delight in it as if he said that's
how you abandon it that's how you stop
feeding it it doesn't mean if you
approved craving for food doesn't mean
you stop eating for the rest of your
life doesn't mean you'll be unaware of
the preferential taste so to speak but
none of it will be rooted in you craving
being pressured towards that food and
consequently being upset on account of
not getting it
or being bothered on account of not
getting enough of it so that's I mean
the only way you can discern whether
you're acting under pressure or not is
to first see what acting is occurring
what thoughts are there and so sometimes
it's bad to think about food but not
because of the thought of food but
because it's rooted in the pressure and
sometimes it's not bad to think about
food because you won't be rooted in the
pressure but if all you can see is
thoughts of food you'll never see where
they're rooted you'll never see where
the pressure is means you'll never see
where the dam is in the practice
and if you can't see in that direction
you'll never see that that when you
arrive you yeah that pressure is
dependent on something yeah